Julia Newman: "Into the Fire" Research Materials: Partial Inventory ALBA.226
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Julia Newman: "Into the Fire" Resources, 366004
  - Stills: "Spanish Civil War Stills Tape 1." 60-minute U-Matic video., Oct 1, 1992; 366501 (Box 7, Item 226-174)
  - Interview: "Irene Goldin Spiegel Women of the Spanish Civil War." 60-minute U-Matic video., Mar 8, 1996; 366502 (Box 7, Item 226-175)
  - Archival footage: "Doc. Films #1." 60-minute U-Matic video. (Original from the Southern California Library for Social Research.), Undated; 366504 (Box 7, Item 226-176)
  - Archival footage: "Doc. Films #1 part 1." 60-minute U-Matic video. (Original from the Southern California Library for Social Research.), Undated; 366505 (Box 7, Item 226-177)
  - Archival footage: "Doc. Films #2 part 2." 60-minute U-Matic video. (Original from the Southern California Library for Social Research.), Undated; 366554 (Box 7, Item 226-178)
  - Archival footage: "Espagne Ombres Et Lumiere de la Republique tape 3 part 1." 60-minute U-Matic video., Sep 29, 2000; 366555 (Box 7, Item 226-179)
  - Archival footage: "Espagne Ombres Et Lumiere de la Republique tape 3 part 2." 60-minute U-Matic video., Undated; 366556 (Box 7, Item 226-180)
  - Archival footage: "Filmoteca Archival Part 1 of 3." U-Matic video., Sep 29, 2000; 366557 (Box 7, Item 226-181)
  - Archival footage: "D'Brigades Internationales tape 1." 30-minute U-Matic video., Sep 29, 2000; 366558 (Box 7, Item 226-182)
  - Archival footage: "Spain Brigades Internationales." U-Matic video., Jan 4, 2001; 366559 (Box 7, Item 226-183)
  - Archival footage: "Martha Gellhorn BBS Omnibus." U-Matic video. (Original from BBC Omnibus.), Dec 4, 1991; 366560 (Box 7, Item 226-184)
  - Archival footage: "Civil War in Spain PSN 5771,6307,6003,6800." 60-minute U-Matic video. (Original from Greinberg Film Libraries.), Oct 2, 2000; 366561 (Box 8, Item 226-185)
  - Work copy: "Into the Fire." 60-minute U-Matic video., Jan 10, 2002; 366562 (Box 8, Item 226-186)
  - Archival footage: "Spanish Civil War." 20-minute U-Matic video. (Original from Pathe Archives.), Sep 29, 2000; 366563 (Box 8, Item 226-187)
  - Archival footage: "Filmoteca Archival Part 2 of 3." 60-minute U-Matic video. (Original from Filmoteca.), Sep 29, 2000; 366564 (Box 8, Item 226-188)
  - Archival footage: "Filmoteca Archival Part 3 of 3." 60-minute U-Matic video. (Original from Filmoteca.), Sep 29, 2000; 366565 (Box 8, Item 226-189)
  - Archival footage: "1) Espana 2) Grenade Ma Grenade 3) Madrid En Flammes Tape 2 part 1 of 3." 60-minute U-Matic video., Oct 2, 2000; 366566 (Box 8, Item 226-190)
  - Archival footage: "1) Espana 2) Grenade Ma Grenade 3) Madrid En Flammes Tape 2 part 2 of 3." 60-minute U-Matic video., Oct 2, 2000; 366567 (Box 8, Item 226-191)
  - Archival footage: "1) Espana 2) Grenade Ma Grenade 3) Madrid En Flammes Tape 2 part 3 of 3." 60-minute U-Matic video., Oct 2, 2000; 366568 (Box 8, Item 226-192)
  - Archival footage: "Defenders of the Faith 1 of 2." 60-minute U-Matic video., Sep 29, 2000; 366569 (Box 8, Item 226-193)
  - Archival footage: "Defenders of the Faith 2 of 2." 60-minute U-Matic video., Sep 29, 2000; 366570 (Box 8, Item 226-194)
  - Archival footage: "The Spanish Earth." 60-minute U-Matic video., Sep 29, 2000; 367299 (Box 8, Item 226-195)
  - Interview: "Celia Greenspan A Clarkson." 60-minute U-Matic video. (Original from CBC.), 1992; 367300 (Box 8, Item 226-196)
  - Interview: "Sunday Morning Comrades 2 Celia/Adrienne Clarkson." 60-minute U-Matic video., Undated; 367301 (Box 8, Item 226-197)
  - Stills: "Spanish Civil War Stills Tape 2 Reel 2." 60-minute U-Matic video., Oct 1, 1992; 367302 (Box 8, Item 226-198)
  - Archival footage: "Forever Activist." 60-minute U-Matic video., Undated; 367303 (Box 8, Item 226-199)
  - Promo: "Their Cause Was Liberty." 15-minute VHS videotape., Jun 5, 2000; 367304 (Box 9, Item 226-200)
  - Promo: "Their Cause Was Liberty." 20-minute VHS videotape., Sep 21, 1999; 367305 (Box 9, Item 226-201)
  - Promo: "Their Cause Was Liberty." 15-minute VHS videotape., May 20, 1999; 367306 (Box 9, Item 226-202)
  - Video: "Their Cause wWs Liberty." 30-minute VHS., Undated; 367307 (Box 9, Item 226-203)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 Tape 1 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Jul 1996; 367308 (Box 9, Item 226-204)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 Tape 2 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Jul 1996; 367309 (Box 9, Item 226-205)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 Tape 6 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Jul 1996; 367310 (Box 9, Item 226-206)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 Tape 7 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Jul 1996; 367311 (Box 9, Item 226-207)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 Tape 8 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Jul 1996; 367312 (Box 9, Item 226-208)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 Tape 9 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Jul 1996; 367313 (Box 9, Item 226-209)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 Tape 10 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Jul 1996; 367314 (Box 9, Item 226-210)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 Tape 12 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Jul 1996; 367315 (Box 9, Item 226-211)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 Tape 13 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Jul 1996; 367316 (Box 9, Item 226-212)
  - Promo: "PI/EP Their Cause was Liberty." 15-minute VHS videotape., Sep 21, 1999; 367317 (Box 9, Item 226-213)
  - Archival footage: "Adrienne Clarkson presents Bethune #2A NY." 30-minute VHS videotape. (Original from CBC.), Dec 11, 2000; 367318 (Box 9, Item 226-214)
  - Archival footage: "The Last Cause Episodes 1 & 2." 120-minute VHS videotape., Undated; 367319 (Box 9, Item 226-215)
  - Archival footage: "The Last Cause Episode 3." 120-minute VHS videotape., Undated; 367320 (Box 9, Item 226-216)
  - Promo: "Their Cause was Liberty." 20-minute VHS videotape., Undated; 367321 (Box 9, Item 226-217)
  - Video: "Parraga Family Spain '96 [with Amaya Paraga]." 45-minute VHS., 1996; 367322 (Box 9, Item 226-218)
  - Archival footage: "Leves Avant Le Jour." 90-minute VHS videotape., Oct 7, 2000; 367323 (Box 9, Item 226-219)
  - Archival footage: "Espagne Vivra." 90-minute VHS videotape. (Original from Cina-Archives.), Aug 17, 2000; 367324 (Box 9, Item 226-220)
  - Archival footage: "Guernica Guerre D'Espagne." 150-minute VHS videotape. (Original from Cinemateque Gaumont.), Jun 27, 2000; 367325 (Box 9, Item 226-221)
  - Archival footage: "Actualite Guerre D'Espagne." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Cinemateque Gaumont.), Jun 27, 2000; 367326 (Box 9, Item 226-222)
  - Archival footage: "Guernica Guerre D'Espagne." 150-minute VHS videotape. (Original from Cinemateque Gaumont.), Jun 27, 2000; 367327 (Box 9, Item 226-223)
  - Archival footage: "Martha Gellhorn." 120-minute VHS videotape. (Original from BBC Omnibus.), Oct 18, 1991; 367328 (Box 9, Item 226-224)
  - Archival footage: "The Spanish Civil War." 120-minute VHS videotape., Undated; 367329 (Box 9, Item 226-225)
  - Archival footage: "Our World May 21 1987, Our World Jan- May 1937 Jarama." 120-minute VHS videotape., 367330 (Box 9, Item 226-226)
  - Archival footage: "Spanish Civil War." 120-minute VHS videotape. (Original from National Archives.), Undated; 367331 (Box 9, Item 226-227)
  - Archival footage: "The Spanish Earth." 120-minute VHS videotape. (Original from Nation Archives.), Undated; 367332 (Box 9, Item 226-228)
  - Video: "BI '96 11." 60-minute VHS., 1996; 367333 (Box 9, Item 226-229)
  - Video: "BI '96 12." 60-minute VHS., 1996; 367334 (Box 9, Item 226-230)
  - Archival footage: "ACP Bethune #1A." 30-minute VHS videotape. (Original from CBC.), 1996; 367335 (Box 9, Item 226-231)
  - Video: "Homenaje 1996 TVE Madrid Concert." 120-minute VHS., 367336 (Box 9, Item 226-232)
  - Video: "Informe- Brigades Intl' 14 tvi." 30-minute VHS., Undated; 367337 (Box 9, Item 226-233)
  - Archival footage: "Five Tom Mooney Films." 90-minute VHS. (Original from the Southern California Library for Social Research.), Undated; 367338 (Box 9, Item 226-234)
  - Video: "TV Barcelona 1996." 15-minute VHS., 367339 (Box 9, Item 226-235)
  - Archival footage: "Footage from 1937." 10-minute VHS videotape. (Original from the UCLA Film and TV Archive.), Undated; 367340 (Box 9, Item 226-236)
  - Archival footage: "San Diego Youth Demonstration Kern County Cotton Strike." 30-minute VHS videotape. (Original from the Southern California Library for Social Research.), Nov 15, 2001; 367341 (Box 9, Item 226-237)
  - Archival footage: "Films Spanish Civil War." 120-minute VHS videotape. (Original from the National Archives.), Undated; 367342 (Box 9, Item 226-238)
  - Archival footage: "Filmoteca Espanol." 180-minute VHS videotape. (Original from Filmoteca.), Undated; 367343 (Box 9, Item 226-239)
  - Video: "Spain '96 Tape 5 Amaya [Paraga] @ Jarama cemetary Tape 7 Amaya and Paragas." 60-minute VHS videotape., 1996; 367345 (Box 9, Item 226-240)
  - Interview: "Their Cause was Liberty Vienna Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Tape 1." 60-minute VHS videotape., Nov 30, 1995; 367346 (Box 10, Item 226-241)
  - Interview: "Their Cause was Liberty Vienna Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Tape 2." 60-minute VHS videotape., Nov 30, 1995; 367347 (Box 10, Item 226-242)
  - Interview: "Their Cause was Liberty Vienna Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Tape 3." 60-minute VHS videotape., Nov 30, 1995; 367348 (Box 10, Item 226-243)
  - Interview: "Their Cause was Liberty Vienna Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Tape 4." 60-minute VHS videotape., Nov 30, 1995; 367349 (Box 10, Item 226-244)
  - Interview: "Their Cause was Liberty Vienna Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Tape 5." 60-minute VHS videotape., Nov 30, 1995; 367350 (Box 10, Item 226-245)
  - Interview: "Their Cause was Liberty Vienna Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Tape 6." 60-minute VHS videotape., Nov 30, 1995; 367351 (Box 10, Item 226-246)
  - Interview: "Their Cause was Liberty Vienna Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Tape 7." 60-minute VHS videotape., Nov 30, 1995; 367352 (Box 10, Item 226-247)
  - Interview: "Their Cause was Liberty Vienna Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Tape 8." 60-minute VHS videotape., Nov 30, 1995; 367353 (Box 10, Item 226-248)
  - Interview: "Their Cause was Liberty Vienna Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Tape 9." 60-minute VHS videotape., Nov 30, 1995; 367354 (Box 10, Item 226-249)
  - Interview: "Esther Silverstein Blanc Tape 1." 60-minute VHS videotape., Apr 28, 1995; 367355 (Box 10, Item 226-250)
  - Interview: "Helen Freeman Feinberg." 120-minute VHS videotape., Dec 5, 1993; 367356 (Box 10, Item 226-251)
  - Archival footage: "Spanish Civil War 1972 16mm cut work print." 30-minute VHS videotape., Mar 4, 1997; 367357 (Box 10, Item 226-252)
  - Archival footage: "Martha Gelhorn." 120-minute VHS videotape. (Original from BBC Omnibus.), Dec 4, 1991; 367358 (Box 10, Item 226-253)
  - Archival footage: "Chronicles of Hope A." 120-minute VHS videotape., Jan 23, 1995; 367359 (Box 10, Item 226-254)
  - Archival footage: "Chronicles of Hope B." 60-minute VHS videotape., Jan 23, 1995; 367360 (Box 10, Item 226-255)
  - Video: "Hommage '96 Madrid TVE." 60-minute VHS., Jan 2, 1997; 367361 (Box 10, Item 226-256)
  - Archival footage: "Defenders of the Faith." 120-minute VHS videotape. (Original from Fast Images.), Sep 14, 2000; 367362 (Box 10, Item 226-257)
  - Video: "Spanish Civil War between the Wars." 30-minute VHS., Undated; 367363 (Box 10, Item 226-258)
  - Video: "on line video." 60-minute VHS., 1996; 367364 (Box 10, Item 226-259)
  - Archival footage: "Veilles D'Armes 1." 120-minute VHS videotape., Jun 2, 2000; 367365 (Box 10, Item 226-260)
  - Archival footage: "Veilles D'Armes 2." 120-minute VHS videotape., Jun 2, 2000; 367366 (Box 10, Item 226-261)
  - Archival footage: "Veilles D'Armes 3." 120-minute VHS videotape., Jun 2, 2000; 367367 (Box 10, Item 226-262)
  - Archival footage: "Lincoln Brigade Footage from 1937." 10-minute VHS videotape. (Original from UCLA Film and TV Archive.), Jan 27, 1999; 367368 (Box 10, Item 226-263)
  - Archival footage: "Ione Paris." 120-minute VHS videotape., Jun 2, 2000; 367369 (Box 10, Item 226-264)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 tape 3 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Nov 1996; 367370 (Box 10, Item 226-265)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 tape 4 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Nov 1996; 367371 (Box 10, Item 226-266)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 tape 5 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Nov 1996; 367372 (Box 10, Item 226-267)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 tape 9 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Nov 1996; 367373 (Box 10, Item 226-268)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 Tape 10 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Nov 1996; 367374 (Box 10, Item 226-269)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 tape 11 Spain Nov. '96" 60-minute VHS., Nov 1996; 367375 (Box 10, Item 226-270)
  - Video: "International Brigades '96 Tape 13 Spain Nov. '96." 60-minute VHS., Nov 1996; 367376 (Box 11, Item 226-271)
  - Video: "Ruth and Hilda, Judy's 1986 and parts of 41 and 42 46 and 47." 120-minute VHS., Undated; 367377 (Box 11, Item 226-272)
  - Video: "Demo Reel." 30-minute VHS., Sep 12, 1990; 367378 (Box 11, Item 226-273)
  - Archival footage: "Benicasim" 16mm film., Undated; 444717 (Box 11, Item 226-274)
  - Archival footage: "S. Schiff Part 3 Abraham Lincoln Brigade" 16mm film., Undated; 444718 (Box 11, Item 226-275)
  - Archival footage: "Filmoteca Nacional de Espana; Prisioneros" 16mm film., Undated; 444719 (Box 11, Item 226-276)
  - Archival footage: Unlabeled [newsreel?] 16mm film., Undated; 444720 (Box 11, Item 226-277)
  - Archival footage: "Miscellaneous 1936-1937" 16mm film., 444721 (Box 11, Item 226-278)
  - Archival footage: "Bottcher, Gates, Thompson, Nelson, Merriman, Barsky + others" 16mm film., 444722 (Box 11, Item 226-279)
- Series II: Unprocessed Records, 1 Linear Feet in 1 record carton (Box 1, Box 12, Box 13, Box 14, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22)